The Battleground Is Your Barracks
The Invisible War is a documentary, war, crime film directed by Kirby Dick.
An investigative and powerfully emotional documentary about the epidemic of rape of soldiers within the US military, the
institutions that perpetuate and cover up its existence, and its profound personal and social consequences.
Self - US Coast Guard, played by Kori Cioca.
Self - US Air Force, played by Jessica Hinves.
Self - US Marine Corps, played by Ariana Klay.
Self - US Marine Corps, played by Elle Helmer.
Self - US Navy, played by Hannah Sewell.
Self - US Navy, played by Trina McDonald.
The Invisible War is a 2012 American documentary film written and directed by Kirby Dick and produced by
Amy Ziering and Tanner King Barklow about sexual assault in the United States military.
It premiered at the 2012 Sundance Film Festival, where it received the U.S.
Documentary Audience Award.
The film has been lauded by advocates, lawmakers, and journalists for its influence on
government policies to reduce the prevalence of rape in the armed forces.
The Invisible War is the recipient of a Peabody Award and Emmy Awards for Best
Documentary Feature and Outstanding Investigative Journalism.
It was nominated for Best Documentary Feature at the 85th Academy Awards.
The film explores themes of rape, post-traumatic stress
disorder (ptsd), sexism, rape victim, family.
The tone is emotional.